# MILDRED MAKORI SOFTWARE ENGINEER

+254 711 711 701 • GitHub • LinkedIn • Medium • twitter

### PERSONAL PROFILE

A Software Engineer graduate specialized in front end web, very passionate, honest, loves learning and enjoys being challenged. Looking to secure a position to use and further develop my skills in a practical, fast-paced environment. Has used tactical and, team-focused approaches to drive people to project completion. I have 5 yrs experience in UX/UI

# SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript | CSS/CSS3 | Sass | HTML5 | C | TypeScript Frameworks/Libraries: Reactjs | npm | NodeJS | jQuery| Tailwind CSS | Python Flask | SQL | WordPress | Bash/git | Bootstrap

Version Control: GitHub

Database Management: MYSQL | MongoDB

Design Tools: Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Photoshop, Canva, Invision

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MiRo Technologies -Co-founder & Team Lead March 2018 to present Responsible for leading a team of 4 people tasked with improving front-end deployments that were not agile and taking up 2 hours, and reduced it to 1 hour.

- Troubleshoot website problems & Create and test applications for websites & Responsible for Hiring,
- Training our clients on how to use specific software in case they encounter any challenges.

UCESCO Africa -Web developer & designer Nov 2022 to Present Create and test applications for websites, Troubleshoot website broblems.

Maintain and update the website & Monitor website traffic. Which n return increased up to 70% funding and page visits.

Introduced online payment, to curb the key pain points experienced by donors using offline payments which in return increased to almost 120% donations increase!

General design/redesign of the website.

EldoHub -Web Developer & Designer (Remote) -Contract March 2021 to June 2021.

Built an e-commerce website in WordPress to digitize the process of bnline shopping, Which in return generated a 7% profit margin.

Andela -Front Engineering Intern -Contract March 2021 - June 2021 Was Responsible for website design and development for the

Led update sync meetings on the status of the websites during prints that translated to positive attendance and beating the broject deadline.

Deveint -Front-End Engineer Intern -Jan 2017 - April 2017

Create and test applications ensuring edge cases is tested and

AkiraChix - Volunteer -April 2016 - May 2016

Assisted over 10 children with projects on Arduino programming, developing and designing websites, and helped them enhance their crafting skills through art projects.

# PRE-PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Call Center interviewer at Consumer
- Headgirl at Chemamul High school

#### EDUCATION

2021 - 2022

ALX (Holberton)-Software Engineering-

2016

AkiraChix- Web & Graphic Designer

2012 - 2015

The Technical University of Kenya(TUK)- Diploma in Aeronautical Engineering

#### CERTIFICATIONS

Azure Fundamentals by Microsoft

### **INTERESTS**

Keen Interest in Research and development in tech industry and poverty alleviation

### **NOTABLE PROJECTS**

Career spike- A job board platform to list entry level jobs Housefy- a platform to list houses to rent and buy

#### REFEREES

Available upon request